# 大家好 今天下雨哦
Hi everyone! It's raining today.
# 剛好沒甚麼肉吃 上那個上面還有幾隻鴨子
I've just run out of meat. Let's go up, I mean, up there. There are still a couple of ducks.
# 我現在做一個啤酒鴨來
I'm now gonna make a beer duck.
# 搞點這像草餵一下那個豬
Let me get some elephant grass here for the pig.
# 豬絕食了 不吃
The pig is on hunger strike. It doesn't eat.
# 去餵一下那個小豬
I'm gonna feed that piggy.
# 把這個象草給它吃
I'll give it the elephant grass.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 看它吃不吃
Let's see if it's eating.
# 嗯 它會吃哦
Um! It's eating!
# 好斯文啊這條豬
It has a very good manner, this pig.
# 不怎麼吃哦
It doesn't eat much.
# 明天再不吃的話我就磿刀了哦
You'll see me sharpening my knife if you don't start eating something by tomorrow, got it?
# 吃那麼一點點 就這樣子吃
It eats just a tiny little bit, bit by bit.
# 你看 它會吃一點 沒事啦 應該是養的活這頭豬
Look! It's eating a little bit. It should be fine. I should be able to make it survive, this pig.
# 準備抓鴨
Get ready to catch a duck!
# 鴨跑哪裡去啦
Where are the ducks?
# 你看 一下就抓住啦
Look! I got it in a single grab.
# 不反抗的哦
It didn't resist at all.
# 不用看 下次就輪到你啦
You don't need to watch. It will be your turn next time.
# 它竟然不怕
Why isn't it scared?
# 烤鴨
Grilled duck!
# 嘎嘎
Ga ga!
# 好啦 這個鴨子
Alright! This duck...
# 拔不乾淨的 就這樣 有一點點
Here's still some feather. Here, a tiny little bit.
# 一點毛也可以吃的 這個毛
A little bit of feather is edible, the feather here.
# 還有一點點毛
There's still a tiny little bit of feather.
# 這個鴨子砍好啦 就那麼一點點
So I've chopped up the duck. Just a tiny little bit here.
# 我搞點子薑 來湊一下
I've fetched some young ginger, to make it a dish.
# 湊下去就多一點 這樣子吃 不然太少啦
Then we can have more to eat. Otherwise, it's too few here.
# 不夠吃啊
It won't be enough for us.
# 你看 把這個鴨子炒一下
Look! I'm gonna fry the duck for a while.
# 搞點油
Put some oil.
# 因為這個鴨子沒甚麼油 要多放點油
We need a bit more oil, cuz there's hardly any oil in the duck.
# 把這個生薑先放下去炸一下
I put the ginger into the wok and fry it for a while.
# 把鴨子 把這個鴨子燜熟 燜熟之後再來 再來煮
I'll stew it, stew the duck, until it's done. And then I'll, I'll cook it for another while.
# 你看這個鴨子 一點肥肉都沒有
Look! This duck is completely free of fat.
# 煮這個鴨子比較費油
Cooking this duck needs quite a lot of oil.
# 所以油要放多一點
So we have to put a bit more oil.
# 放點鹽
Put some salt.
# 鹽都不出來 放多一點
The salt doesn't come out. Put more salt.
# 這個香葉和八角 放下去
Here are bay leaves and star anise. Put them in.
# 放點這個啤酒
Put some this kind of beer.
# 這三瓶都放下去
We put all these three cans.
# 鴨子 啤酒鴨
Duck! Beer duck!
# 就這樣慢慢燜 小火慢慢燜
We just keep stewing it, on low heat.
# 把它蓋起來
Cover it up.
# 誒呦 剛剛好哦
Ayo! It fits perfectly well!
# 這個啤酒鴨做好啦
So the beer duck is done.
# 味道杠杠的
C'est délicieux!
# 鴨個雞腿來吃
Let me have a chicken leg.
# 這個鴨腿
This duck leg,
# 好有嚼勁哦
is really chewy.
# 味道很不錯
It tastes really not bad.
# 山葯 王剛 要不要一起來 花式啤酒美味挑戰
Yam, Wang Gang! You wanna join? Freestyle Beer Delicacy Challenge.
# 味道絕對OK 經過我的調養 你們看它的肉質
The taste is absolutely OK, after my special care. Have a look at its texture!
# 一點肥肉都沒有
It's completely free of fat.
# 吃一頓 餓三餐
I feed it not every meal, but every four meals.
# 餵出來的鴨子
Then the ducks are,
# 就是好
nothing but good.
# 像這個鴨子 (註︰他應該是說︰「你看這個鴨子」)
Have a look at the duck!
# 除了瘦肉就是骨頭 還有一層皮
Except lean meat, there's only bone, and skin.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻就到這裡啦 我們準備吃晚飯啦
The video ends here. We're getting ready to have our dinner.
# 給這大肥狗
It's for this big fat dog.
# 一直都沒吃到
He couldn't get anything.